<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - Vcards by TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en/category/uncategorized/</link>
	<description>Go digital. Go green.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 12:45:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/favicon-01-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - Vcards by TicTAP</title>
	<link>/en/category/uncategorized/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Define your brand&#8217;s image</title>
		<link>/en/define-your-brands-image/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olinta Lopez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 13:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When we talk about brand image, we are referring to the perception that a brand wants people to have of it. This article is the first part in which we are going to develop the basic elements that make up the definition of this image and the reasons why it is an essential element in &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/define-your-brands-image/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Define your brand&#8217;s image</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/define-your-brands-image/">Define your brand&#8217;s image</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When we talk about brand image, we are referring to the perception that a brand wants people to have of it. This article is the first part in which we are going to develop the basic elements that make up the definition of this image and the reasons why it is an essential element in the development of a company&#8217;s marketing strategy. In the second part of the article, which will be published the following week, we will focus on how to execute a brand image campaign and what tools can help us along the way.</p>

<p>If you are starting a new project, you are still not clear about your brand image or you want to change it and renew the one you had originally, the first thing you have to do is to identify how your solution contributes to improving the lives of your users. For example, if we are talking about a luxury fashion brand, this brand brings a social status to its customers, it gives them a sense of exclusivity and elitism, since whoever wears these clothes will feel like one of the privileged few in the world with access to be able to buy them. On the other hand, a sports fashion brand mainly brings comfort, durability and practicality to those who wear its clothes and accessories to exercise. What are the main characteristics of your product or service and how can it positively impact the lives of those who consume it?</p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15718" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/7811254-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption style="font-size:9px;"><a href="https://www.freepik.es/vector-gratis/ilustracion-concepto-creacion-marca_31385200.htm#query=brand&amp;position=2&amp;from_view=search&amp;track=sph">Imagen de storyset</a> en Freepik</figcaption></figure>

<p></p>

<p>Secondly, you should consider what is the most human identity of your company, what is your philosophy? If you are a family business that has been in the sector for decades and you follow your own production process, you can promote concepts such as proximity, tradition and trust. On the other hand, if you are a young company that is aware of current social struggles, such as equality, the environment or racism, you can make known how important some of these causes are in your decision making.</p>

<p></p>

<p>Thirdly, you need to know what your potential customers are like, in order to connect with the audience you need to know what their habits and needs are and where your brand fits into their lives, from their point of view. To do this, analyse the data you have on your customers and also ask them personally to better understand what behaviour patterns they may follow and what value your product or service has for them.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/group-of-casually-dressed-business-people-discussing-ideas-in-the-office-1-min-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption style="font-size:9px;"><a href="https://www.freepik.es/foto-gratis/grupo-hombres-negocios-ocasional-vestidos-que-discuten-ideas-oficina_4691888.htm?query=brand">Imagen de tirachardz</a> en Freepik</figcaption></figure>

<p>Now that we have defined the message and the image that we want to accompany our brand, we will execute a marketing strategy to make it known. In the second part of this article we will talk about what we need to study about the market and the competition and what are the advertising tools that will help us to expand. Stay tuned for next week&#8217;s post.</p>

<p></p>

<p>If you’ve made it this far, thanks for reading this article! To contact us, send us an email to <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me">vcards@tictap.me</a>. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news. Read other articles:</p>

<p><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/how-to-improve-engagement/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to improve engagement</span></i></a></p>

<p><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest essential for conventions</span></i></a></p>

<p><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</span></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/define-your-brands-image/">Define your brand&#8217;s image</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The latest essential for conventions</title>
		<link>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/</link>
					<comments>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olinta Lopez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 23:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital business cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vcards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The main objective of the fairs and exhibitions is publicize your company or project and connect with people who may be interested in investing in it or buy your products or hire your services. It’s one of the most widely distributed contact cards and brochures. But are they effective? many times they are not because &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The latest essential for conventions</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/">The latest essential for conventions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The main objective of the fairs and exhibitions is<strong> publicize your company or project and connect with people who may be interested in investing in it or buy your products or hire your services</strong>. It’s one of the most widely distributed contact cards and brochures. But are they effective? many times they are not because they get lost or end up in the trash, and you lose an opportunity to offer not only your data but the opportunity to book an appointment, or offer a sample of what you have to offer.</p>

<p>So what alternative is there?</p>

<p>Ideally, you should be able to share your contact and relevant business information with interested visitors quickly, easily and effectively. This is possible with vcards by TicTAP. Just by showing a QR code on your mobile, the other person will scan it on theirs, and<strong> your contact information (name, email, and telephone number) and links to your website and to the vcard platform, will be transferred to their contact book.</strong> From there they will see catalogues, videos, and much more. <strong>You choose what content to upload!</strong></p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="725" height="380" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15422" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas.png 725w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas-300x157.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 725px) 100vw, 725px" /></figure>

<p></p>

<p>When using vcards at trade fairs, you will enjoy greater comfort, as you can tour the stands without the need to load with a large number of papers to distribute. In addition, since we carry our mobile phones everywhere, you will have the security of always having with you what you need to present your solution.  You’ll be saving time and money on printing materials, and most importantly, you’ll be contributing positively to the environment!</p>

<p>Digital business cards, known as vcards, are the solution that offers you much more than just sharing your personal data.</p>

<p>If you want to know more, you can contact us by sending an email to <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me">vcards@tictap.me</a> or you can read our articles <em><a href="https:/vcards.tictap.me/que-sonlas-vcards/">What are vcards? </a></em> and <em><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/paperless-actions-sustainable-en-el-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/">The latest essential for conventions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
