<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/sin-categorizar/</link>
	<description>IoT Marketing Platform</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 13:48:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/favicon-01-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<link>/category/sin-categorizar/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to improve engagement</title>
		<link>/en/how-to-improve-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 13:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vcard TicTAP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=13673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term engagement has been gaining a lot of relevance during recent years in most companies&#8217; marketing strategies. This article explains what it implies, how it can help you grow your business, and some ways and tools to optimize it. In marketing, engagement refers to the interactions we have with customers or social media users &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to improve engagement</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="13673" class="elementor elementor-13673 elementor-13669">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-a573f19 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="a573f19" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-f4a77fb" data-id="f4a77fb" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-5a02f8fd elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="5a02f8fd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p></p>
<p>El concepto <em><strong>engagement </strong></em>ha estado ganando mucha relevancia en los últimos años en las estrategias de marketing de la mayoría de empresas. En este artículo te explicamos qué implica, cómo puede ayudarte a hacer crecer tu negocio, y algunas maneras y herramientas para optimizarlo.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Cuando hablamos de <em>engagement </em>nos referimos a la<strong> interacción que mantenemos con nuestros clientes o con usuarios de redes sociales que pueden ser nuestros clientes potenciales</strong>. Las interacciones con tu perfil o publicaciones pueden ser: dar me gusta, dejar un comentario, contestar a una encuesta, compartir en su perfil o mediante mensaje a uno de sus amigos, enviarte un mensaje directo y guardar la publicación para consultarla más adelante. Estas son las formas de interactuar más frecuentes y que dan más resultados.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Tener muchos seguidores no es sinónimo de que una cuenta esté bien posicionada en redes sociales, ya que los seguidores se pueden comprar y porque puede que muchos de esos usuarios hubieran empezado a seguir a la cuenta hace tiempo y aunque ya no les interese su contenido tampoco les molesta porque ni siquiera se les muestra en su página principal. Esto se debe a que <strong>la mayoría de algoritmos dan prioridad en mostrar el contenido con el que más interactúa el usuario,</strong> ya que entiende que es el más le interesa.</p><p><br></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2><strong>¿Por qué es importante mantener un buen <em>engagement </em>en tus redes sociales?</strong></h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>En primer lugar, es lo que <strong>hará que tu marca tenga más alcance</strong>, ya que si el algoritmo detecta tu contenido como interesante para algunos usuarios, se lo recomendará a otros con gustos similares. En segundo lugar, es una <strong>manera de fidelizar a tus clientes</strong>. Si a los usuarios que conocen tu marca y ya han probado alguno de tus productos o servicios les <strong>aportas un valor añadido creando contenido que les sirva de ayuda y de entretenimiento</strong>, conseguirás que se identifiquen con tu marca y te conviertas en un referente en ese sector para ellos, acudiendo a ti para repetir la transacción o probar otros de tus productos.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Ahora te preguntarás, <strong>¿cómo puedo conseguir tener un buen engagement con mi comunidad?</strong> Como he mencionado anteriormente, tienes que crear contenido de calidad y que a tus seguidores les aporte. Para esto primero tienes que <strong>conocer bien las necesidades y las aspiraciones de tu audiencia</strong>. También ten en cuenta que para captar su atención tiene que ser digerible y de alguna manera entretenido.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Pero muchas veces aunque al usuario le haya resultado interesante tu publicación no interactúa con ella o quizás solamente indica que le gusta. Para lograr una interacción en el que el usuario responda o comente puedes difundir tu contenido en otros canales como por ejemplo Discord o Telegram. Cada vez más, influencers y marcas están habilitando grupos en estas plataformas para promover el <em>engagement </em>con sus seguidores de una manera más activa. Esto sobre todo funciona en los casos en los cuales los perfiles en redes sociales ya tienen cierto reconocimiento y cuentan con una comunidad formada.</p><p><br></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<h2><strong>¿Qué puedes hacer para que tus clientes y prospectos interactúen activamente con el contenido que creas para ellos si no estás establecido en una red social o quizás tu audiencia no es tan activa?</strong></h2>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Las tarjetas de visita digitales por vcards by TicTAP suponen una solución a este problema. Si no sabes lo que son las vcards puedes informarte al respecto en menos de 5 minutos leyendo nuestro artículo: <a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/que-son-las-vcards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">¿Qué son las vcards?</a></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>A través de nuestras vcards puedes compartir mucho más que tu información de contacto ya que sus funcionalidades van más allá que las de una tarjeta de presentación. Puedes enviar <strong>notificaciones push</strong> para incentivar a que los usuarios que tengan tu contacto guardado interactúen con el nuevo contenido que cuelgas en la vcard, <strong>rellenando encuestas de todo tipo, enviando preguntas al momento, o navegando a través del menú en el que encontrarán videos o presentaciones</strong> creadas por ti para ellos.&nbsp;</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>También podrás <strong>enlazar y concentrar en la vcard todos tus perfiles en redes sociales</strong> para asegurarte que tu comunidad sabe donde encontrarte e ir creciendo tu presencia a través de esta plataforma. Las vcards by TicTAP son una herramienta muy útil para mantener una comunicación cercana con tus clientes potenciales y existentes.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>Sí has llegado hasta aquí, ¡gracias por leer este artículo! Para ponerte en contacto con nosotros envíanos un correo electrónico a vcards@tictap.me. Suscríbete a nuestro boletín de noticias aquí para mantenerte al día con nuestras novedades.</p>
<p></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is an online business card?</title>
		<link>/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 10:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[vcard TicTAP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-is-an-online-business-card/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A business card or business card online is the business card always digitized. In other words, instead of having a paper business card, you have a digital card that is accessed through a QR code or a link.  Traditionally, in meetings or networking events came a time when you exchanged your business card with a &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is an online business card?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/">What is an online business card?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="12985" class="elementor elementor-12985 elementor-8514">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-7685b1e8 tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="7685b1e8" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-56a0c477" data-id="56a0c477" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-0559408 tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="0559408" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-e2adecf" data-id="e2adecf" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c595c75 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c595c75" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>A business card or business card online is the business card always digitized. In other words, instead of having a paper business card, you have a digital card that is accessed through a QR code or a link.  </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-14b42b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="14b42b6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Traditionally, in meetings or networking events came a time when you exchanged your business card with a potential customer, provider or a contact that could be interesting for your work or your business. </p>
<p>In recent years the digital business card, or digital business card, has appeared. At first there was some suspicion. Therefore, many professionals and companies continued to bet on the card in cardboard or paper of a lifetime. </p>
<p>One of the barriers mentioned was that the impact created by the paper card was irreplaceable. Of course, for this it was necessary that it had a design and paper very well chosen and according to the brand.  </p>
<p>However, the VOCID-19 pandemic arrived. The tide turned overnight. As a result, events (meetings, fairs, congresses&#8230;) have been digitized. So in many causes networking is not done by physical presence but in videoconferences, etc.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-145016f elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="145016f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="558" height="381" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment.jpg 558w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment-300x205.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 558px) 100vw, 558px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-466a2b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="466a2b6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Paper cards have no place in this environment. It is in it precisely where digital business cards take over as a new substitute. </p>
<p>With an online business card you can continue to share your contact details easily using a QR code, a link, etc. There are different platforms to create your digital business cards. Depending on the platform, you can share them in one way or another. </p>
<p>Apart from the fact that you will be able to share it in the new environment we are facing due to the pandemic, the online business card has many other advantages to consider. They also have some not so positive aspects or limitations that you should not underestimate.  </p>
<p>If you want to know the pros and cons of Online Business Card to see if this card format suits you, we invite you to know them in our article <a href="/9-advantageous-and-3-inconveniences-of-digital business cards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9 advantages and 3 disadvantages of digital business cards</a>. </p>
<p>So, adapting to the strong current digitization trend that we are in right now is easy, then, in terms of your business cards. You can see here how we can help you with the <a href="/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TicTAP vCards</a>.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/">What is an online business card?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
