<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en/</link>
	<description>IoT Marketing Platform</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 15:02:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/favicon-01-150x150.png</url>
	<title>TicTAP</title>
	<link>/en/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</title>
		<link>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/</link>
					<comments>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 19:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term paperless refers to a reduction in the use of paper, a strategy commonly applied to the working or studying space. We are a company committed to the environment and in this article, we will focus on why and how to bring your office closer to being paperless. Reasons to digitize your work and &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="14156" class="elementor elementor-14156 elementor-14152">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-5b10b0a2 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="5b10b0a2" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-2d4019ef" data-id="2d4019ef" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6e83627b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="6e83627b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				
<p>El término paperless se refiere a la <strong>disminución del uso del papel</strong>, medida comúnmente aplicada al espacio de trabajo o de estudios. Somos una empresa comprometida con el medio ambiente y en este artículo nos centraremos en algunos de los motivos por qué y cómo acercar tu oficina a ser paperless.</p>

<p> </p>

<h2><strong>Motivos por los que digitalizar tu trabajo y dejar de usar papel</strong></h2>

<p>La razón principal por la cual deberías disminuir el consumo de papel es por el impacto perjudicial que ocasiona en el <strong>medio ambiente</strong>. La producción y distribución del papel supone la tala de árboles, el gasto de agua, el uso de productos químicos tóxicos y las emisiones emitidas por el transporte desde la fábrica a tu oficina. Después de su uso se suele convertir en un desecho que muchas veces no es correctamente reciclado.</p>

<p>Otra de los motivos por los cuales considerar bajar el consumo de papel es el <strong>ahorro económico</strong> que supone. No estarías gastando en comprar papel, tinta ni otros materiales, ni también en el espacio físico que a veces se requiere para almacenar la documentación o el coste de mantenimiento que muchas impresoras requieren.</p>

<p>Por último, la <strong>efectividad que aporta la transformación digital</strong> al mundo laboral es también una ventaja. Tener la documentación en un espacio virtual permite que se pueda trabajar en conjunto desde diferentes puntos geográficos y de una manera inmediata. También permite la sencilla integración entre aplicaciones.</p>

<p> </p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="640" height="722" class="wp-image-14163" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873.jpg" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873-266x300.jpg 266w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></figure>

<p> </p>

<h2><strong>Acciones recomendadas para conseguir ser paperless</strong></h2>

<p>El primer paso que debes tomar hacia la transformación digital es contratar <strong>servicios de almacenamiento en la nube</strong>. Seguramente ya lo estés haciendo en alguna medida, pero intenta que todos los proyectos y tareas que tu equipo lleven a cabo se hagan a través del espacio de trabajo virtual. También puedes tener un bloc de notas siempre abierto para ir apuntando tus ideas y utilizar aplicaciones que te ayuden a organizarte, sin tener que recurrir a la libreta tradicional.</p>

<p>El siguiente paso es <strong>digitalizar tu firma</strong>. Aunque la mayoría de empresas trabajan en su mayoría solo con el ordenador, siguen imprimiendo documentos que requieren firmas para después escanearlos y devolver el envío. Estos pasos te los puedes ahorrar y puedes agilizar el proceso contratando un servicio de digitalización de firmas.</p>

<p>El último paso que te recomendamos implementar y con el que te podemos ayudar es a <strong>deshacerte de las tarjetas de visita tradicionales, los folletos y los catálogos y pasarte a las vcards</strong> (si no sabes que son este artículo te explica todo lo que necesitas saber en un par de minutos: <em><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/que-son-las-vcards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">¿Qué son las vcards?</a></em>).</p>

<p>Con las tarjetas de contacto digitalizadas estarás reduciendo considerablemente el consumo de papel y estarás conectando de una manera más efectiva. Además, a través de las vcards by TicTAP podrás también compartir la misma información que repartirías en folletos o presentarías en catálogos, pero de una manera <strong>más práctica, dinámica, económica y sostenible</strong>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12938 size-medium aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-300x286.png" alt="" width="300" height="286" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-300x286.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-1024x976.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-768x732.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></figure>

<p> </p>

<p>¿Tu empresa está siguiendo una estrategia hacia la digitalización y sostenibilidad? ¿Qué más medidas recomendarías desde tu experiencia? Gracias por leer este artículo y te invitamos a que lo compartas y continúes leyendo otros de nuestro <a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/blog/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blog</a>. Si tienes alguna duda o te interesaría información no dudes en contactarnos en <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vcards@tictap.me</a>.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to improve engagement</title>
		<link>/en/how-to-improve-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 13:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=13673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term engagement has been gaining a lot of relevance during recent years in most companies&#8217; marketing strategies. This article explains what it implies, how it can help you grow your business, and some ways and tools to optimize it. In marketing, engagement refers to the interactions we have with customers or social media users &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to improve engagement</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The term <strong>engagement</strong> has been gaining a lot of relevance during recent years in most companies&#8217; marketing strategies. This article explains what it implies, how it can help you grow your business, and some ways and tools to optimize it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In marketing, engagement refers to the <strong>interactions we have with customers or social media users who may be potential customers.</strong> Interactions with your profile or posts may include: liking, leaving a comment, answering a survey, sharing it on their profile or sending it in a message to one of their friends, sending a direct message and saving the post to see it later. These are some of the most frequent ways of interacting and that give more results.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having many followers doesn’t mean that an account is well positioned on social networks, as followers can be bought and because many of those users may have started following the account a long time ago and even if they’re no longer interested in it’s content, they’re not bothered because it’s not even shown on their homepage. This is because <strong>most algorithms give priority to displaying the content that the user interacts with the most</strong>, as they understand that this is the content that interests them the most.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Why is it important to maintain a good level of engagement on your social networks? </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On first place, <strong>it will make your brand have more reach</strong>, because if the algorithm detects your content as interesting for some users, it will recommend it to others with similar tastes. On second place, because <strong>it’s a way to build customer loyalty</strong>. If you<strong> provide added value to users</strong> who know your brand and have already tried one of your products or services <strong>by creating content that helps them and entertains them</strong>, you’ll make them identify with your brand and become a benchmark in that sector for them, and they’ll come to you to repeat the transaction or try other of your products.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13683 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-860x1024.webp" alt="women engaging" width="860" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-860x1024.webp 860w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-252x300.webp 252w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-768x915.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-1290x1536.webp 1290w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851.webp 1597w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now you may ask yourself, <strong>how can I get a good engagement with my community?</strong> As I mentioned before, you have to create quality content that your followers will enjoy. To do this you first need to <strong>know the needs and aspirations of your audience</strong>. Also keep in mind that to capture their attention it has to be digestible and somehow entertaining.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But many times, even if the user finds your publication interesting, he/she does not interact with it or perhaps only indicates that he/she likes it. To achieve an interaction in which the user responds or comments you can spread your content on other channels such as Discord or Telegram. Increasingly, influencers and brands are setting up groups on these platforms to promote engagement with their followers in a more active way. This especially works in cases where the social media profiles already have some presence and a built-up community.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>What can you do to get your customers and prospects to actively interact with the content you create for them if you are not established on a social network or perhaps your audience is not as active?</strong> </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards by TicTAP’s digital business cards are a solution to this problem. If you don&#8217;t know what vcards are, you can find out in less than 5 minutes by reading our article: <a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through our vcards you can share much more than just your contact information as their functionalities go beyond those of a business card. You can send <strong>push notifications</strong> to encourage users who have your saved contact to interact with the new content you post on the vcard, <strong>filling out surveys of all kinds, sending questions on the spot, or browsing through the menu where they will find videos or presentations </strong>created by you for them.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13678 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-1024x700.png" alt="menu vcards by TicTAP" width="1024" height="700" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-1024x700.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-300x205.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-768x525.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1.png 1049w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You&#8217;ll also be able to <strong>link and concentrate all your social media profiles in the vcard</strong> to make sure your community knows where to find you and grow your presence through this platform. Vcards by TicTAP are a very useful tool to keep a close communication with your potential and existing customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve made it this far, thanks for reading this article! To contact us, send us an email to <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me">vcards@tictap.me</a>. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are vcards?</title>
		<link>/en/what-are-vcards/</link>
					<comments>/en/what-are-vcards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[About vcards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-are-vcards/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Vcards are the digital version of traditional business cards. They are a tool that’s turning upside down how we connect.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards are the digital version of traditional business cards. They are a </span><b>tool that’s turning upside down how we connect with companies and between people</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They work in a simple way, by means of a QR code on your mobile you share your vcard with whoever you want to connect, for example, a prospect, an investor or a colleague. When the person scans the QR on their mobile, your information and the link to the card are automatically saved in their contact book. You can also </span><b>share it through a link</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by direct messages or email or adding it in your social media profile.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards are an ecological and economical solution to the waste of single use paper caused by traditional business cards. If you decide to make the change, you will be adopting a</span><b> sustainable measure that will also save you money and with which you will ensure that your contact information is not lost or forgotten</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as it often happens with many paper business cards. Vcards are also dynamic as they allow you to change the data and have it updated instantly.</span></p>
<figure><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/friends-talking-while-texting-in-cafe.jpg" alt=""></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The market consists of a wide variety of brands that offer digital business cards, but </span><b>vcards by TicTAP are the only 360 option</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, here’s why:</span></p>
<p><b>#offline</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> They also work without signal or internet connection.</span></p>
<p><b>#noapp</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Neither you nor the other person need to download an app.</span></p>
<p><b>#content</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Share multimedia content such as photos, videos, presentations or brochures.</span></p>
<p><b>#traceable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> They can be integrated with CRMs, ERPs or Analytics to measure interactions.</span></p>
<p><b>#languages</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ​​The information will be displayed in the language of the user who scans it.</span></p>
<p><b>#multi-brand </b>and <strong>#multi-branch</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Set up different vcards for each brand, line of business and branch.</span></p>
<p><b>#engagement</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Interact with users through forms and surveys.</span></p>
<p><b>#customizable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We customize your vcards following the design of your brand.</span></p>
<p><b>#self-manageable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can manage them autonomously through our platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&#8217;ve made it this far,</span><b> thanks for reading this article!</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> To contact us, send us an email to </span><a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me"><span style="font-weight: 400;">vcards@tictap.me</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/what-are-vcards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is an online business card?</title>
		<link>/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 10:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-is-an-online-business-card/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A business card or business card online is the business card always digitized. In other words, instead of having a paper business card, you have a digital card that is accessed through a QR code or a link.  Traditionally, in meetings or networking events came a time when you exchanged your business card with a &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is an online business card?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/">What is an online business card?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="12985" class="elementor elementor-12985 elementor-8514">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-7685b1e8 tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="7685b1e8" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-56a0c477" data-id="56a0c477" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-0559408 tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="0559408" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-e2adecf" data-id="e2adecf" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c595c75 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c595c75" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>A business card or business card online is the business card always digitized. In other words, instead of having a paper business card, you have a digital card that is accessed through a QR code or a link.  </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-14b42b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="14b42b6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Traditionally, in meetings or networking events came a time when you exchanged your business card with a potential customer, provider or a contact that could be interesting for your work or your business. </p>
<p>In recent years the digital business card, or digital business card, has appeared. At first there was some suspicion. Therefore, many professionals and companies continued to bet on the card in cardboard or paper of a lifetime. </p>
<p>One of the barriers mentioned was that the impact created by the paper card was irreplaceable. Of course, for this it was necessary that it had a design and paper very well chosen and according to the brand.  </p>
<p>However, the VOCID-19 pandemic arrived. The tide turned overnight. As a result, events (meetings, fairs, congresses&#8230;) have been digitized. So in many causes networking is not done by physical presence but in videoconferences, etc.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-145016f elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="145016f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="558" height="381" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment.jpg 558w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tictap-vcard-for-digitalized-environment-300x205.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 558px) 100vw, 558px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-466a2b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="466a2b6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Paper cards have no place in this environment. It is in it precisely where digital business cards take over as a new substitute. </p>
<p>With an online business card you can continue to share your contact details easily using a QR code, a link, etc. There are different platforms to create your digital business cards. Depending on the platform, you can share them in one way or another. </p>
<p>Apart from the fact that you will be able to share it in the new environment we are facing due to the pandemic, the online business card has many other advantages to consider. They also have some not so positive aspects or limitations that you should not underestimate.  </p>
<p>If you want to know the pros and cons of Online Business Card to see if this card format suits you, we invite you to know them in our article <a href="/9-advantageous-and-3-inconveniences-of-digital business cards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9 advantages and 3 disadvantages of digital business cards</a>. </p>
<p>So, adapting to the strong current digitization trend that we are in right now is easy, then, in terms of your business cards. You can see here how we can help you with the <a href="/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TicTAP vCards</a>.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-is-an-online-business-card/">What is an online business card?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 advantages and 3 drawbacks of digital business cards</title>
		<link>/en/9-advantages-and-3-drawbacks-of-digital-business-cards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 07:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[About vcards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/9-advantages-and-3-drawbacks-of-digital-business-cards/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital business cards have their advantages and disadvantages, like everything else in this life. Let’s have a look at these virtues and limitations so you can decide if it’s in your best interest to give way to the digitalization of your presentation and contact tool. Without being a spoiler, I will advance you that digital &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/9-advantages-and-3-drawbacks-of-digital-business-cards/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">9 advantages and 3 drawbacks of digital business cards</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/9-advantages-and-3-drawbacks-of-digital-business-cards/">9 advantages and 3 drawbacks of digital business cards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="12031" class="elementor elementor-12031 elementor-9772">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-7685b1e8 tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="7685b1e8" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-56a0c477" data-id="56a0c477" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-8dec5eb elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="8dec5eb" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Digital business cards have their advantages and disadvantages, like everything else in this life. Let’s have a look at these virtues and limitations so you can decide if it’s in your best interest to give way to the digitalization of your presentation and contact tool.</p><p><i>Without being a spoiler, I will advance you that digital business cards can be very useful. However, they are very limited with respect to Smart business cards, as we will also see in this article. </i></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b6d1e56 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="b6d1e56" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PHONE_FLOOR_CARD_4-min.png" title="" alt="" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-93f5e1d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="93f5e1d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>Advantages of digital business cards</h2><h3>1. Ideal during the pandemic</h3><p>With the current situation the face-to-face meetings have declined. A large part of these meetings are now made through calls and videoconferences. This transformation has not only occurred for meetings. Other events such as fairs are being held in digital format. </p><p>In this new environment, traditional paper business cards are completely obsolete. You can’t give them to the client, since you’re probably not even physically reunited. A digital business card is the solution, as it will allow you to easily share it using the QR code or facilitating the link contact-less to the person of interest.</p><h3>2. Flexible and more varied content</h3><p>Apart from the first name, surname, position, address, email and telephone, a digital business card allows you to include many other types of content. Some examples of this are: links to social networks, the curriculum and information on the work experience of the holder, etc.</p><p>In addition, if at any time any data changes (name of the position, address, telephone&#8230;) the update is immediate. </p><p>With the paper format, you would have to throw them all away and wait for printing, or cross out and write the new data by hand, and ask for more updates.</p><h3>3. Collaborate to take care of the environment with digital business cards</h3><p>Being digital you avoid paper and, not only that, but also printing, inks, etc. In this way you get contribute to the improvement and care of the environment.</p><p>This point is also especially interesting because many times business cards end up in the trash even before the person who received it registers it on their mobile. That is to say, that all those natural resources used or the impact they cause on the environment, they do not contribute anything to the growth of your business, sales, etc.</p><p>You can believe that this point is not so important either. But today brands can no longer just say &#8220;We do things well, with quality&#8221;, because the public already usually take these two points for granted. They don’t make you any different. That’s why branding is changing and businesses are turning more and more to values.</p><p>If you stop to think about the ads you see today, how many talk about doing things well and how much more importance is given to other values such as safety, freedom, being a winner, or good parents or having quality of life if you consume their product&#8230;</p><p>Ecology and sustainability are two good values with which more and more people connect. If they are among the hesitation to buy from two potential suppliers, these values are the ones that can add extra points to move the balance for one of them and discard the one that does not.</p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9dbe9a7 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="9dbe9a7" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/forest-paper-waste.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/forest-paper-waste.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/forest-paper-waste-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/forest-paper-waste-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-26ddbbd elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="26ddbbd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>4. Lower cost for its creation</h2><p>The logistic and economic cost of traditional business cards is high. You don’t just have to pay for materials and printing. In many companies with a staff of workers already a little large, they end up having a person who dedicates part of his work to the task of collecting data for new cards, check that they are correct, talk to the printer&#8230;</p><p>this person usually creates an excel or a Google spreadsheet. It includes all the details of the new cards to be ordered. Once this is done he sends it to the design department, or to the external design studio that prepares the design if there has been any change in it. Once you have the originals you should review them, because if there is an error there will be no going back after printing.</p><p>Finally, the files have been validated and sent to printing. If there has been no change in design, the printer will still ask you to validate the data before printing. This person will always have to review and validate the data at each step of the process. If anything is wrong, it will be modified and sent back to the company for the person to validate if the files are completely correct now, before printing them. This whole process ends up being very slow and consuming many hours for a company person.</p><p>Digital business cards avoid these costs. The person in charge of making the business cards of the company can directly enter the data of the new workers or modify the existing ones in the application or digital card platform.</p><p>If you want to change the design, you will have to go through the design part, but it will be much more agile and simple because you do not have the limitations of printing. If a data is incorrect, even if the person responsible for making the digital cards is not aware, it is enough for the cardholder to communicate it to that responsible person so that at a time he enters the card management platform and modifies it. No extra costs and always more agile than with the paper format.</p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c3f946a elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="c3f946a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-helps-reduce-costs.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-helps-reduce-costs.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-helps-reduce-costs-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-helps-reduce-costs-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-adfd977 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="adfd977" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>5. Lower cost in data logging</h2>
<p>Paper business cards mean that if you go to a meeting you give a card to the other person and the other person, after the meeting, will have to register it on his mobile and save it in his physical card box at the office. This entails two limitations:</p>
<ol>
<li>It is possible that the other person forgets after registering it and your data falls into oblivion of a jacket or wallet. </li>
<li>If the person receiving your card does not forget, they will register it when they arrive at their office, or give it to their assistant to do so. This record is a waste of time in a mechanical task that does not bring any kind of professional growth or interest to who does it, whether it is your direct contact or his assistant. </li>
</ol>
<p>The situation gets worse if instead of a meeting the event was a fair or a congress. In these types of events, the contacts you have made do not return to your office with just your card, but with a good handful of them. As a result, the time spent recording the data is significantly increased. What’s more, it’ll be the same for you with all the cards you get, too. </p>
<p>With digital business cards, who receives the card registers it directly on your mobile. With the vCard format, introducing the card into the company’s digital card registration system will also be much more agile and comfortable. </p>
<h3>6. Digital business cards are always available</h3>
<p>With digital business cards you just have to make sure that you have your mobile, and with battery, of course! Although this probably<span style="font-size: 20px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400;"> is already taken into account in your networking events and current meetings. </span></p>
<p>Therefore, it will no longer be the case that you forget the cards in the office or in the car, or that you run out and have to wait to print more again. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6df377d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="6df377d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-vcards-always-available.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-vcards-always-available.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-vcards-always-available-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tictap-vcards-always-available-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ad1f8b2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="ad1f8b2" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2><span style="font-size: 26px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;">7. Multi channel</span></h2>
<p>Digital business cards usually have several ways to share: QR code, link sending by Whatsapp, email, sms, Bluetooth, social networks&#8230; </p>
<p>How you can share them will depend on the choice of digital card you make and the options that the platform to create it from. </p>
<h3>8. Differentiation</h3>
<p>While your competition continues to give out paper cards, you can introduce yourself with your digital card showing your differentiation in all the details. The first impression is crucial. It can help you create a good impact by presenting yourself with a digital business card that allows your prospects to automatically integrate your data into their mobile and/or contact system without wasting time. </p>
<p>When you talk to them after doing things well, effectively, etc. you will have more credibility when they see that you really move with that way of doing even in the details. </p>
<p>The advantage of differentiation will disappear over time because such cards are more widespread. But even so, its positive impact of ease on data sharing without wasting time, will remain for your prospects and prospects. </p>
<h3>9. Many more possibilities to offer your customers and prospects</h3>
<p>Digital business cards appeared on the market some time ago, but everything that can be offered with them is still being explored. The reality is that more and more possibilities are being added. At TicTAP we differentiate between digital business cards, which are basically the life-long card converted to online format, and Smart business cards.</p>
<p>A Smart business card goes far beyond offering data. It’s about having a digital card that when the other person receives it and opens it is not only with that information, but with many more tools and options. You can even have several sections with text, forms, or send notifications, etc.</p>
<p>In this way, when the other person wants, you can reopen your link or use the QR code you provided in the product you sold, and contact you through a contact form. Or you can do one-to-one marketing campaigns by offering a new product or offer only to contacts you know will be interested. They will receive that message in the form of notification and SMS on their own mobile. </p>
<p>An example of a Smart business card is the TicTAP Vcard. If you want more information about them, you can <a href="/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">find it here</a> . </p>
<p>With the TicTAP vCards, your business cards become a kind of webapp easy to create and maintain for you, which your customers or contacts will be able to access and perceive as if they were a simple application with different options, but will not require any installation on your mobile because they will access through the same web browser of your device. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-1d341eb elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="1d341eb" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Imatgeverdtaca.png" title="" alt="" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-8a4adf1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="8a4adf1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>Disadvantages of digital business cards</h2>
<p>As we have seen, these types of cards have many advantages, but it is not all gold that shines. You need to be well informed about the pros and cons so you can make the decision that is best for you. So let’s now look at the disadvantages that we should also consider:</p>
<h3>1. Design limitations</h3>
<p>This limitation will largely depend on the solution or platform used to create the digital card. Depending on which one is chosen, we can enjoy a wide variety of design possibilities or a few very limited options. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-1f364ba elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="1f364ba" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="768" height="511" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/paper-card-example-768x511.jpg" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/paper-card-example-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/paper-card-example-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/04/paper-card-example.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4385e86 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="4385e86" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>2. Ensure a good design adaptation in devices</h3>
<p>It is true that paper is much more restrictive because it is a limited physical space. But if it has an advantage it is that once printed it is already like that for everyone. It will not change or look different because the person keeps it in a card box or other, etc.</p>
<p>Instead, a digital business card will be seen on a mobile or tablet. The size of the screen will make in some cases, if the screens were not considered very small, the data look poorly positioned or even remain outside the screen. </p>
<p>Although it is true that you can play with the option of scroll for very small screens, or offer different pages and sections (as in the case of ticTAP vCard, etc.) to avoid data saturation on a single screen and be able to give more information at the same time, information and options, it is important to think well about the design and adaptability of your digital business cards. </p>
<p>That is, the design of digital cards should be well taken care to ensure that your virtual business cards:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 20px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400;">adapt correctly to different devices;</span></li>
<li>are functional;</li>
<li>offer high usability to users. </li>
</ol>
<p>And for this, it will be worth investing in the design phase and that someone expert in this area makes a good design that meets all the requirements of use and technical. It’s not just about branding and aesthetics. Otherwise, you may end up with hard-to-read or hard-to-use digital business cards from the recipient. </p>
<p>This point is not exactly a disadvantage but rather a risk in the case of not making a good design. It takes us to the key that well-understood design is both functional and attractive. And it reminds us that, although it is always important in our communication materials, it is still more important in the digital world where it can mean that users do not see the data, etc. if it is not well thought out and adapted. </p>
<h3>3. Acceptance level of digital business cards</h3>
<p>This has been a disadvantage that slowed many professionals and companies to start using this type of card. Many people felt that their target audience would not easily accept such cards, that they would prefer traditional ones or that paper had more impact. </p>
<p>With the pandemic we have advanced at a technological level in a year what we would have advanced in years without it. This is not just an advance on what technologies and the digital world offer. We are also talking about the acceptance of the digital world by companies and society in general. </p>
<p>Thus, the barrier of acceptance of digital business cards seems to have decreased greatly, if not almost disappeared. However, it may still be a possible barrier for some target audience profiles or for certain more conservative sectors. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-14b42b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="14b42b6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2><span style="font-size: 30px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;">Do digital business cards suit you? </span></h2>
<p>After seeing what digital business cards are, their many advantages and their few disadvantages, it is time to make the decision. </p>
<p>If one of the disadvantages has enough weight to unmark all its advantages, the thing is clear. But probably all its advantages will bring you much more, since most of the inconveniences are easily salvageable. In addition, with the current pandemic, the digital world is rapidly gaining positions. </p>
<p>So, the next interesting discussion is rather which digital business card platform, or Smart digital business card, gives you more game when it comes to creating card templates.  </p>
<p>You should also consider the point of how to have a design expert, either internal or external, for the specific design phases that you must do if you see that this point escapes you to do it yourself. Keep in mind that the design phase is primarily to create the template, and then just some more phase when you want to make some design changes or add some functionality. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/9-advantages-and-3-drawbacks-of-digital-business-cards/">9 advantages and 3 drawbacks of digital business cards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
