<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Angela Peralta, Author at Vcards by TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/author/angela/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/author/angela/</link>
	<description>Go digital. Go green.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 23:50:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/favicon-01-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Angela Peralta, Author at Vcards by TicTAP</title>
	<link>/author/angela/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The latest essential for conventions</title>
		<link>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/</link>
					<comments>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 23:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital business cards are the solution that enable you to leave behind traditional paper cards. If you&#8217;re not aware of what these are, we recommend you read our article ¿What are cards?, in which we explain everything you need to know to get started. In this article we&#8217;ll give you the reasons for why you &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The latest essential for conventions</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/">The latest essential for conventions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Digital business cards are the solution that enable you to leave behind traditional paper cards. If you&#8217;re not aware of what these are, we recommend you read our article<a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/what-are-vcards/"><em> ¿What are cards?</em></a>, in which we explain everything you need to know to get started. In this article we&#8217;ll give you the reasons for why you need to take them with you to the next conventions you attend.</p>

<p></p>

<p>The main objective of conventions and exhibitions is to publicize your company or project and connect with people who may be interested in investing in it or buying your products or hiring your services. It is one of the scenarios in which contact cards and brochures are distributed the most, but many times they are not very effective, because they get lost or end up in the bin.</p>

<p></p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="725" height="380" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15422" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas.png 725w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/risas-300x157.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 725px) 100vw, 725px" /></figure>

<p></p>

<p>Ideally, you should be able to share your contact and relevant business information with interested visitors quickly, easily and effectively. This is possible with vcards by TicTAP. Just by showing a QR code on your mobile, the other person will scan it on theirs, and<strong> your contact information (name, email, and telephone number) and links to your website and to the vcard platform, will be transferred to their contact book.</strong> From there they will see catalogues, videos, and much more. <strong>You choose what content to upload!</strong></p>

<p></p>

<p>With <strong>vcards you will gain more comfort  at conventions</strong> since you will be able to move around the stands without having to carry a mountain of paper to distribute. Wherever we go we always take our mobile phones with us so <strong>you can ensure that you&#8217;ll always have what you need to present with you your solution.</strong> You&#8217;ll also have saved time and money in printing the material, and most importantly, you will favor the environment!</p>

<p></p>

<p><article id="post-13673" class="post-13673 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-marketing-en ast-article-single">&#13;
<div class="ast-post-format- single-layout-1">&#13;
<div class="entry-content clear">&#13;
&#13;
If you’ve made it this far, thanks for reading this article! To contact us, send us an email to <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me">vcards@tictap.me</a>. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news. Read other articles:&#13;
&#13;
</div>&#13;
</div>&#13;
</article><nav class="navigation post-navigation" aria-label="Posts"></nav></p>

<p><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/how-to-improve-engagement/"><i>How to improve engagement</i></a></p>

<p><em><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/">The latest essential for conventions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/the-latest-essential-for-conventions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</title>
		<link>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/</link>
					<comments>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 19:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term paperless refers to a reduction in the use of paper, a strategy commonly applied to the working or studying space. We are a company committed to the environment and in this article, we will focus on why and how to bring your office closer to being paperless. Reasons to digitize your work and &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="14156" class="elementor elementor-14156 elementor-14152">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-5b10b0a2 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="5b10b0a2" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-2d4019ef" data-id="2d4019ef" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6e83627b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="6e83627b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				
<p>El término paperless se refiere a la <strong>disminución del uso del papel</strong>, medida comúnmente aplicada al espacio de trabajo o de estudios. Somos una empresa comprometida con el medio ambiente y en este artículo nos centraremos en algunos de los motivos por qué y cómo acercar tu oficina a ser paperless.</p>

<p> </p>

<h2><strong>Motivos por los que digitalizar tu trabajo y dejar de usar papel</strong></h2>

<p>La razón principal por la cual deberías disminuir el consumo de papel es por el impacto perjudicial que ocasiona en el <strong>medio ambiente</strong>. La producción y distribución del papel supone la tala de árboles, el gasto de agua, el uso de productos químicos tóxicos y las emisiones emitidas por el transporte desde la fábrica a tu oficina. Después de su uso se suele convertir en un desecho que muchas veces no es correctamente reciclado.</p>

<p>Otra de los motivos por los cuales considerar bajar el consumo de papel es el <strong>ahorro económico</strong> que supone. No estarías gastando en comprar papel, tinta ni otros materiales, ni también en el espacio físico que a veces se requiere para almacenar la documentación o el coste de mantenimiento que muchas impresoras requieren.</p>

<p>Por último, la <strong>efectividad que aporta la transformación digital</strong> al mundo laboral es también una ventaja. Tener la documentación en un espacio virtual permite que se pueda trabajar en conjunto desde diferentes puntos geográficos y de una manera inmediata. También permite la sencilla integración entre aplicaciones.</p>

<p> </p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="722" class="wp-image-14163" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873.jpg" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-mart-production-7550596-e1669382290873-266x300.jpg 266w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></figure>

<p> </p>

<h2><strong>Acciones recomendadas para conseguir ser paperless</strong></h2>

<p>El primer paso que debes tomar hacia la transformación digital es contratar <strong>servicios de almacenamiento en la nube</strong>. Seguramente ya lo estés haciendo en alguna medida, pero intenta que todos los proyectos y tareas que tu equipo lleven a cabo se hagan a través del espacio de trabajo virtual. También puedes tener un bloc de notas siempre abierto para ir apuntando tus ideas y utilizar aplicaciones que te ayuden a organizarte, sin tener que recurrir a la libreta tradicional.</p>

<p>El siguiente paso es <strong>digitalizar tu firma</strong>. Aunque la mayoría de empresas trabajan en su mayoría solo con el ordenador, siguen imprimiendo documentos que requieren firmas para después escanearlos y devolver el envío. Estos pasos te los puedes ahorrar y puedes agilizar el proceso contratando un servicio de digitalización de firmas.</p>

<p>El último paso que te recomendamos implementar y con el que te podemos ayudar es a <strong>deshacerte de las tarjetas de visita tradicionales, los folletos y los catálogos y pasarte a las vcards</strong> (si no sabes que son este artículo te explica todo lo que necesitas saber en un par de minutos: <em><a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/que-son-las-vcards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">¿Qué son las vcards?</a></em>).</p>

<p>Con las tarjetas de contacto digitalizadas estarás reduciendo considerablemente el consumo de papel y estarás conectando de una manera más efectiva. Además, a través de las vcards by TicTAP podrás también compartir la misma información que repartirías en folletos o presentarías en catálogos, pero de una manera <strong>más práctica, dinámica, económica y sostenible</strong>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12938 size-medium aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-300x286.png" alt="" width="300" height="286" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-300x286.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-1024x976.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1-768x732.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/09/imatge-4-1.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></figure>

<p> </p>

<p>¿Tu empresa está siguiendo una estrategia hacia la digitalización y sostenibilidad? ¿Qué más medidas recomendarías desde tu experiencia? Gracias por leer este artículo y te invitamos a que lo compartas y continúes leyendo otros de nuestro <a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/blog/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blog</a>. Si tienes alguna duda o te interesaría información no dudes en contactarnos en <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vcards@tictap.me</a>.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/">Paperless &#8211; Sustainable actions at work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/paperless-sustainable-actions-at-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to improve engagement</title>
		<link>/en/how-to-improve-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 13:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=13673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term engagement has been gaining a lot of relevance during recent years in most companies&#8217; marketing strategies. This article explains what it implies, how it can help you grow your business, and some ways and tools to optimize it. In marketing, engagement refers to the interactions we have with customers or social media users &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to improve engagement</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The term <strong>engagement</strong> has been gaining a lot of relevance during recent years in most companies&#8217; marketing strategies. This article explains what it implies, how it can help you grow your business, and some ways and tools to optimize it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In marketing, engagement refers to the <strong>interactions we have with customers or social media users who may be potential customers.</strong> Interactions with your profile or posts may include: liking, leaving a comment, answering a survey, sharing it on their profile or sending it in a message to one of their friends, sending a direct message and saving the post to see it later. These are some of the most frequent ways of interacting and that give more results.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having many followers doesn’t mean that an account is well positioned on social networks, as followers can be bought and because many of those users may have started following the account a long time ago and even if they’re no longer interested in it’s content, they’re not bothered because it’s not even shown on their homepage. This is because <strong>most algorithms give priority to displaying the content that the user interacts with the most</strong>, as they understand that this is the content that interests them the most.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Why is it important to maintain a good level of engagement on your social networks? </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On first place, <strong>it will make your brand have more reach</strong>, because if the algorithm detects your content as interesting for some users, it will recommend it to others with similar tastes. On second place, because <strong>it’s a way to build customer loyalty</strong>. If you<strong> provide added value to users</strong> who know your brand and have already tried one of your products or services <strong>by creating content that helps them and entertains them</strong>, you’ll make them identify with your brand and become a benchmark in that sector for them, and they’ll come to you to repeat the transaction or try other of your products.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13683 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-860x1024.webp" alt="women engaging" width="860" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-860x1024.webp 860w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-252x300.webp 252w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-768x915.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851-1290x1536.webp 1290w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pexels-photo-4353618-e1667396750851.webp 1597w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now you may ask yourself, <strong>how can I get a good engagement with my community?</strong> As I mentioned before, you have to create quality content that your followers will enjoy. To do this you first need to <strong>know the needs and aspirations of your audience</strong>. Also keep in mind that to capture their attention it has to be digestible and somehow entertaining.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But many times, even if the user finds your publication interesting, he/she does not interact with it or perhaps only indicates that he/she likes it. To achieve an interaction in which the user responds or comments you can spread your content on other channels such as Discord or Telegram. Increasingly, influencers and brands are setting up groups on these platforms to promote engagement with their followers in a more active way. This especially works in cases where the social media profiles already have some presence and a built-up community.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>What can you do to get your customers and prospects to actively interact with the content you create for them if you are not established on a social network or perhaps your audience is not as active?</strong> </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards by TicTAP’s digital business cards are a solution to this problem. If you don&#8217;t know what vcards are, you can find out in less than 5 minutes by reading our article: <a href="https://vcards.tictap.me/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through our vcards you can share much more than just your contact information as their functionalities go beyond those of a business card. You can send <strong>push notifications</strong> to encourage users who have your saved contact to interact with the new content you post on the vcard, <strong>filling out surveys of all kinds, sending questions on the spot, or browsing through the menu where they will find videos or presentations </strong>created by you for them.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13678 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-1024x700.png" alt="menu vcards by TicTAP" width="1024" height="700" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-1024x700.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-300x205.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1-768x525.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/11/menu-1.png 1049w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You&#8217;ll also be able to <strong>link and concentrate all your social media profiles in the vcard</strong> to make sure your community knows where to find you and grow your presence through this platform. Vcards by TicTAP are a very useful tool to keep a close communication with your potential and existing customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve made it this far, thanks for reading this article! To contact us, send us an email to <a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me">vcards@tictap.me</a>. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/how-to-improve-engagement/">How to improve engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are vcards?</title>
		<link>/en/what-are-vcards/</link>
					<comments>/en/what-are-vcards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Angela Peralta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[About vcards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-are-vcards/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Vcards are the digital version of traditional business cards. They are a tool that’s turning upside down how we connect.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards are the digital version of traditional business cards. They are a </span><b>tool that’s turning upside down how we connect with companies and between people</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They work in a simple way, by means of a QR code on your mobile you share your vcard with whoever you want to connect, for example, a prospect, an investor or a colleague. When the person scans the QR on their mobile, your information and the link to the card are automatically saved in their contact book. You can also </span><b>share it through a link</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by direct messages or email or adding it in your social media profile.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vcards are an ecological and economical solution to the waste of single use paper caused by traditional business cards. If you decide to make the change, you will be adopting a</span><b> sustainable measure that will also save you money and with which you will ensure that your contact information is not lost or forgotten</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as it often happens with many paper business cards. Vcards are also dynamic as they allow you to change the data and have it updated instantly.</span></p>
<figure><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/friends-talking-while-texting-in-cafe.jpg" alt=""></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The market consists of a wide variety of brands that offer digital business cards, but </span><b>vcards by TicTAP are the only 360 option</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, here’s why:</span></p>
<p><b>#offline</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> They also work without signal or internet connection.</span></p>
<p><b>#noapp</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Neither you nor the other person need to download an app.</span></p>
<p><b>#content</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Share multimedia content such as photos, videos, presentations or brochures.</span></p>
<p><b>#traceable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> They can be integrated with CRMs, ERPs or Analytics to measure interactions.</span></p>
<p><b>#languages</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ​​The information will be displayed in the language of the user who scans it.</span></p>
<p><b>#multi-brand </b>and <strong>#multi-branch</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Set up different vcards for each brand, line of business and branch.</span></p>
<p><b>#engagement</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Interact with users through forms and surveys.</span></p>
<p><b>#customizable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We customize your vcards following the design of your brand.</span></p>
<p><b>#self-manageable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can manage them autonomously through our platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&#8217;ve made it this far,</span><b> thanks for reading this article!</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> To contact us, send us an email to </span><a href="mailto:vcards@tictap.me"><span style="font-weight: 400;">vcards@tictap.me</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Subscribe to our newsletter here to stay up to date with our latest news.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-are-vcards/">What are vcards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Vcards by TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/en/what-are-vcards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
